ORIGINAL WORK BY TATSUYA ENDO
SERIALIZED ON SHUEISHA'S SHONEN JUMP PLUS
It's the day of the battle.
Check your belongings.
-All good.
-Appearance check.
All good.
Final check on speech.
It's good. I'll try my best!
I'm worried, but I did everything I could.
Now it's time
for the Eden Academy interview!
MISSION: 4
AN INTERVIEW AT A PRESTIGIOUS SCHOOL
It's so big!
It's one of the top schools
in the country.
So many applicants…
Everyone is a rival.
Anya, are you okay with the crowd?
Yes!
Then, let's go.
There's no doubt about this feeling.
A feeling I've experienced many times.
Someone's watching me.
-Is there an enemy within the crowd?
-Enemy?
I feel like someone's watching me…
No…
I'm not the only one being watched.
Someone's trying to probe.
It's them. Four in the connecting hallway,
four in the belfry,
and more in the buildings on both sides.
I've memorized the list of
people affiliated with this school.
That's the faculty. I'm sure they're
watching and grading every move
to see if we are
the right fit for this school.
That means
the interview has already started.
Both of you, keep it together.
The examiners are watching us.
Do as we practiced.
-D-68, no.
-A-12, no.
G-114, yes.
The quality of
this year's candidates is low.
Many of them don't have enough elegance.
Good morning, Master.
It's unpleasant to have that crude gait
trudging through the prestigious Eden.
Elegance makes tradition.
Elegance is what makes
the world a paradise.
-Reject all ungraceful families.
-Yes, sir!
Some of them look like they have
a little elegance.
A salute to the statue of
the first president of the Academy?
I, Twilight, who uses
a thousand different faces,
have no difficulty in acting as the
ideal person they want me to be. Watch me!
I have no clue who this is,
but I'm sure it'll be fine
if I just copy Loid.
What a baldy.
Elegant! Very elegant!
Who is that family?
K-212. The Forger family.
Their daughter, Anya's written test
was 31 percent, just short of passing.
Not elegant! And her writing is a mess!
-Did the father remarry?
-Did he marry for admission purposes?
I don't know. We need to check…
whether they have true elegance or not.
We'll check your examination voucher here!
G-114. Go to the first venue.
A-12? Please go to the second venue.
We're already being sifted through.
K-212? Please go to the first venue.
They're still watching us.
Be on your guard.
It makes me nervous to think
they're watching us.
Anya wants to pick her nose.
Absolutely not.
Oh, no!
I accidentally fell into a ditch
-and can't get out!
-No way…
-What should I do? I'm in trouble!
-This is too obvious for a test…
-Do they think he's a lunatic?
-What am I going to do?
-I didn't think there was a ditch here!
-No one's going near him.
However, if this is a test,
we must clear it.
Oh!
Father! Mother! There's a boy in trouble!
I'll go help him!
-Are you all right?
-Help--
Ah! My leg slipped!
I have to do this for credits.
For more credits!
That's right. Your interview is coming up,
but you can't soil your clothes.
How will you pursue this with elegance?
Are you hurt?
I'll give you my handkerchief.
Make sure to be seen
at the medical office.
How disappointing. I guess
he was just a country bumpkin after all.
Don't think you can enter
our schoolhouse covered in mud.
Reject K-212.
These people won't pass,
all because of me…
Um… I'm sorry!
Good thing I brought a change of clothes,
just in case something like this happened!
Who in their right mind
would expect something like this?
This gray one
actually suits this school better.
The other suit may have
made me look like a country bumpkin.
Thank you for giving me
the opportunity to change.
O-Oh…
And on top of everything,
he made the boy feel better!
Smart! Smart and elegant!
-That impudent Loid Forger!
-Master…
-It's a test for the child.
-Shut up!
A child grows up
watching their parents! Yes…
The parents of a 30% child must be 30%!
I'll expose you…
Watch out!
The animals escaped from the corral!
Eden Academy, are you really going to
take things this far?
-Don't push me!
-Get out of the way!
Is this to see everyone's
reaction to an emergency?
If we panic, we'll fall right into
the examiners' trap.
Don't break formation D!
Make sure to treat the animals kindly!
Hey! Who told them to go that far?
Huh? Wasn't it you, Master?
What? This can't be…
A real emergency!
We have some VIPs within our applicants!
Stop them before anyone gets hurt!
I'm the Vice Minister
of the Ministry of Finance!
What do I care?
I work for the central bank as a--
Wait! Dad!
-You were amazing!
-Are you all right?
Loid! Anya isn't feeling well again…
The panic of the crowd must've
gotten to her…
We can't be worried about
the test right now.
He's probably the alpha of the herd.
As long as I stop him…
I need to use my gun… No…
Please watch Anya.
Yor?
It's not what you think!
I used to take yoga classes
and learned a secret technique
to stop movement.
I figured it might work on a cow too…
Please don't be scared!
The cow is scared…
That's dangerous, Anya!
It's okay. It's not scary.
What are you--
They all went home.
Seems so. I'm glad no one got hurt.
E… Ele…
Elegance!
Forger!
He must be the housemaster.
Was he in charge of the test?
Thank you for helping us.
Also, I admit defeat for today.
In order to clear up the chaos,
the interview test will be delayed
and start at a later time.
Come to the venue again
after you've cleaned yourselves up.
All of you are qualified to
get an interview at our school.
Teacher…
Looks like we've been spared.
We appreciate your concern.
However, please don't worry about us.
We thought this might happen,
so we prepared an extra set of clothes.
They're way past elegant.
They're scaring me.
The Forger family
successfully went to the interview.
Did you really try to enter our school
without knowing something like that?
Did you?
Um…
Thank you.
What's with that answer?
I've worked for over ten years as a spy,
and this is the first time
I've been nervous.
I've done an undercover operation
against a nefarious terrorist organization
and stopped a nuclear bomb that was about
to go off with one second to spare,
yet I've never felt this out of breath.
The fear of leaving success or failure
in the hands of others.
Next, the Forger family.
-Yes!
Without a doubt, this is…
Operation Strix's biggest moment of truth!
Excuse us.
Forger. You're here.
The Forger family
will win this information war!
First,
we'll start with questions
for the parents.
Housemaster for Malcom,
the Fifth Dormitory.
Mild-mannered, honest, conservative.
The students trust him.
WALTER EVANS, 59
LANGUAGE TEACHER
If we answer sincerely
and with common sense,
we should get additional points.
It seems like you remarried.
How did your relationship start?
It's an in-depth question,
but it's unique to Eden,
which places importance
on family background.
I met my wife by chance
at a dressmaker that creates
uniforms for this school.
I was attracted by her interesting manner.
Because of my daughter, I had been
cautious since the death of my late wife.
But we clicked over the course of
many conversations.
She is a very kind
and family-oriented person.
I believed that she and my daughter
would get along.
I see. How about you, madam?
W… Well…
Loid is a wonderful man
who cares deeply for his daughter.
He goes out of his way
to make me feel comfortable as well.
I'm glad to hear that
you're a good family.
You're so beautiful, so why did you
bother to choose a man with children?
That's a bit rude, Mr. Swan.
MURDOCH SWAN, 47
ECONOMICS TEACHER
Housemaster of Cline,
the second dormitory.
He was promoted because he's the only son
of the previous headmaster.
He's proud, greedy, and insensitive.
Just last month his wife
asked him for a divorce
and he lost custody of his daughter.
From what I've seen
in the interviews so far,
he's jealous of other families,
and makes hurtful comments.
It'd be best not to provoke him.
Now, onto our next question.
Why did you decide to apply to our school?
This is entirely because…
I want to get close to our enemy Desmond.
…of the high qualifications
of the teachers at your school.
We believe that no one
but the proud teachers at Eden
can teach our daughter
not only quality knowledge and education,
but also patriotic ideals
and the spirit of elitism.
How elegant, Loid Forger.
The type of man I expected you to be.
As her parents, how would you
describe your daughter?
Please tell us
her weaknesses and strengths.
Anya is a child full of curiosity.
She gets into everything,
and you may call that a weakness,
but she's very smart.
Smart? Her?
She sometimes says things
as if she's reading my mind,
so she takes me by surprise.
Her weakness is her picky eating habits.
How about you as the mother?
Do you have an education policy?
Just as we practiced.
As you're aware, I'm not her real mother.
I used to spoil her,
because I wanted her to like me.
But thinking of her future,
I've been working to be
more strict when necessary.
You mentioned earlier
that your daughter is a picky eater.
What kind of meals do you
usually cook at home?
Huh? M… Meals?
I usually cook at home.
Of course when I'm busy,
my wife takes over.
Which has never happened yet.
What?
A wife who doesn't cook actually exists?
You should be more strict on yourself
instead of your daughter!
We all have our strengths and weaknesses.
She likes things neat and tidy,
so our house is perfectly clean.
She also takes very good care
of our daughter.
Well, both of those things are
expected of women.
-That's…
-It's fine, Loid.
-Now…
-That's right. Relax.
What am I getting worked up for?
She's not even my real wife.
A beautiful couple?
So what? Makes me want to gag.
I'll provoke them
and make them show their true colors!
People like this
need to experience failure.
-This world is unfair.
-He doesn't like Father and Mother!
I need to do my best!
Next…
let's go onto questions for your child.
-It's time!
-Can you tell us your name and address?
I'm Anya Forger.
Our address is Berlint, West Ward,
Park Avenue 1…
128!
What do you do on your days off?
-We go to the museum and eat opera…
-Good.
All questions that we expected.
What do you want to do if you're accepted?
Um…
-What was it?
-For me, I'd attend the social gatherings,
and uncover the full extent of
the enemy and its head, Desmond.
I want to uncover
the organization's boss' secrets!
What are you saying?
The organization's boss?
Are you talking about the headmaster?
I'm sorry. My daughter is
more ambitious than most.
She's extremely curious about
the headmaster who stands at the top.
Oh?
Her attitude of trying to
learn from her predecessors
from that age is quite elegant.
Then can you tell us
the name of the headmaster?
Um… Be…
That's right. Benedict Ivan Goodfellow.
Mr. Benejix Avan Goodhella!
So what kind of effort
do you think it takes to
become as successful as he is?
Surviving through a jungle
by relying solely on my body,
and training the spirit by repeatedly
facing life-threatening challenges.
That was the training the main character
was doing in her spy anime.
What determination!
I underestimated her!
I don't think you have to go that far.
Let's change the subject.
What does your father do for work?
A sp-- A spy-tacular psychologist.
Hm? Is your nose a little stuffy?
Then what kind of person
is your new mother?
She's very kind
but she's sometimes scary.
If you were to
rate your father and mother,
what percent would they get?
One hundred percent!
Father and Mother are both fun
and I love them!
I want to be with them forever.
What a load of crap.
Between your new mommy
or your previous mommy,
who would you rate higher?
-Mr. Swan…
-What?
I'd like to ask for a different question.
No. If she doesn't answer,
I'm taking points off.
I don't know how
she ended up in an orphanage,
but her parents are probably already…
Anya…
I see!
You want your previous mommy!
This is too much!
-Relax, Yor.
-But this is--
I need to be patient for the assignment.
We have a lot of students
who are separated from their parents.
She won't last in this school
if she's going to cry over
trivial things like this.
A little slander. So what?
We're a fake family, after all.
Trivial things?
It's nothing.
What, madam?
Don't get feisty, just because
you lost to the previous wife!
Patience, Twilight!
Excuse me.
There was a mosquito.
Thank you for today.
Hey! Where do you think you're going?
We're not done!
If your school's educational philosophy
is to disrespect the feelings of children,
I have chosen the wrong school.
How dare you insult our school!
Let's go, both of you.
Excuse us.
Don't think you'll ever be able to
set foot in our school again!
You went too far, Mr. Swan.
Do you have a problem with my ways?
Despite being a predecessor,
my father's influence is still strong.
You should watch what you say.
Hurry up and call the next family!
We believe that there is no one
but the proud teachers at Eden.
I am not qualified to be an educator
if I keep indulging those with power.
Who's the one who insulted our school?
Huh?
Wha--!
That was quite elegant of me.
Can you now proudly face me
as a teacher at Eden,
Forger?
We've definitely been rejected.
I'll pour some tea.
I'm disqualified as a spy once again.
I brought unnecessary emotions
into the assignment.
Father… I'm sorry.
Anya couldn't do her best for the test.
I'm sorry.
It's fine, Anya.
There's no need to apologize.
I'm sure you wouldn't want to
go there anyway.
-Anya wants to go to school.
-Huh?
If the assignment fails…
If I don't go to school…
…we won't be together anymore.
Anya…
If we're rejected, this life will…
No.
I'm just worried about how
this might affect my work.
But in all honesty,
there's no way we'll pass.
What?
I'm sure it's fine! It'll be all right!
The old man with the glasses,
and the old man with the half glasses
were both good people!
That's right!
They'll push for us!
Let's believe in them!
A spy trusts in no one but himself.
He must always be prepared
for the worst-case scenario.
I want to be with them forever.
But maybe just a little…
You're right.
We'll leave the rest up to fate,
and be happy at how hard we worked
for the test!
Just a little bit, for now…
To our bright future!
Something fell!
Our family portrait fell.
Yes it did.
How successful
was the mission?
NEXT X MISSION
MISSION: 5
PASS OR FAIL?
Subtitle translation by: Nana Onishi